Finding aid for the Office of the Registrar records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Office of the Registrar records
1939-2015
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Office of the Registrar
2.7 linear feet (7 boxes)
This small collection chiefly consists of annual records from the registrar's office, enrollment statistics, correspondence, course catalog preparation materials and some course syllabi.
XUA-86
Scope and Content
This collection gives annual cumulative statistics and listings compiled by the Xavier University Office of the Registrar. Surveys completed by this office are also found in the collection.
Statement of Arrangement
The collection is divided into three series, as follows: Series I. Annual Record Folders, 1951-1974 Series II. Enrollment Statistics, 1939-2006 Series III. Correspondence, Course Catalog Preparation Materials, Syllabi and Associated Printed Materials, 1940-2015
Restrictions on Access
Some materials may have restricted access. Please contact the archives staff.
Acquisition Information
These materials were sent to the archives by the Office of the Registrar.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Administration; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Curricula--Catalogs; Student registration--Ohio--Cincinnati
Detailed Description of The Collection
- I. Annual Records Folders, 1951-1974
  Annual Records for 1962-1963 are missing from this collection.
  - Annual Records, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Records, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual Records, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Records, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Annual Records, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual Records, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual Records, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual Records, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Annual Records, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Annual Records, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Annual Records, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Annual Records, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Annual Records, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Annual Records, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Annual Records, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Annual Records, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Annual Records, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Annual Records, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Annual Records, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Annual Records, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Annual Records, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Annual Records, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Annual Records, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    This folder contains only AJCU enrollment statistics for the 1972-1973 and 1973-1974 academic years.
- II. Enrollment Statistics, 1939-2006
  - Fall Student Enrollment Statistics from 1841 to 2014, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    This folder contains cumulative student enrollment statistics generated in 2014 by Emily Shipley, analyst in the Xavier Office of Institutional Research. Other related materials are also found in the folder.
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, 1951-1953 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, 1954-1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, 1963-1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, Summer, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, Fall, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, Fall, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, Fall, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, Spring, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, 1986-1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, 1993-1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, 2002-2006 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Student Enrollment Statistics and Records, Comparative, 1955-1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    This folder contains various comparative statistics for various years. Not all years are represented in the statistics. The earliest posted year is 1946, the latest being 1982, that being for Edgecliff College students of Xavier University.
- III. Correspondence, Course Catalog Preparation Materials, Syllabi and Associated Printed Materials, 1940-2015
  - Registrar's Correspondence and Reports, 1940-1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Registrar's Correspondence and Reports, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Registrar's Correspondence and Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Registrar's Correspondence and Reports, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Registrar's Correspondence and Reports, 1986-2004 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Course Catalogs (Undergraduate/Graduate) General Information, 2015 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    This folder contains mainly some general information from emails about the Xavier course catalogs and the status of missing catalogs.
  - Teaching Load Studies: Data and Analysis, 1963-1995 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Statistical Studies Other Than Enrollment, 1950-1994 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Classroom Utilization Reports, 1993-1997 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Strategic Scheduling Check-Up For Xavier University, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    This is a study done by Ad Astra Information Systems of Xavier University's academic space and classroom utilization. The study consists of two parts: 1. Capacity Management Study, and 2. Historical Course Analysis. The document is marked as Confidential.
  - Course Syllabi (College of Arts and Sciences), 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Course Syllabi (College of Arts and Sciences), 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - The Second Study: The First College Graduating Class of the New Millennium, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    This appears to have been a study sent to and received by the President's Office.